<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Thea Knowles</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Thea Knowles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing my Twitter dashboard (i.e., finally getting to check off my more wistful to-do&#39;s)</title>
      <link>/post/my-twitter-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-twitter-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>As seems to be habit now, this post turned out a lot longer than I meant for it to. Quick links:
 Check out Joseph Stachelek&#39;s helpful tutorial to implement this yourself (trust me, despite the upcoming wall of text, I made very, very few actual changes to his original implementation, so you should just go straight there for the how-to) Check out my finished project here  Saving tweets for later: Hacky at best When I come across a tweet containing information I would like future-me to take note of, I have a rather inelegant set of strategies for making sure it stays accessible (god forbid I merely rely on remembering; if it’s not down on an externally stored list somewhere outside my brain, it will never see the light of day again):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Twitter dashboard</title>
      <link>/project/my-twitter-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-twitter-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>A searchable database of content I have retweeted as a way of bookmarking them for later. Created by following Joseph Stachelek&#39;s helpful tutorial
 {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;none&#34;,&#34;fillContainer&#34;:true,&#34;data&#34;:[[&#34;2018-06-30&#34;,&#34;2018-06-22&#34;,&#34;2018-06-10&#34;,&#34;2018-06-09&#34;,&#34;2018-06-07&#34;,&#34;2018-06-06&#34;,&#34;2018-06-06&#34;,&#34;2018-06-04&#34;,&#34;2018-06-02&#34;,&#34;2018-06-01&#34;,&#34;2018-05-28&#34;,&#34;2018-05-27&#34;,&#34;2018-05-26&#34;,&#34;2018-05-18&#34;,&#34;2018-05-15&#34;,&#34;2018-05-15&#34;,&#34;2018-05-15&#34;,&#34;2018-05-13&#34;,&#34;2018-05-12&#34;,&#34;2018-05-11&#34;,&#34;2018-05-08&#34;,&#34;2018-05-05&#34;,&#34;2018-05-04&#34;,&#34;2018-05-03&#34;,&#34;2018-05-03&#34;,&#34;2018-05-02&#34;,&#34;2018-04-27&#34;,&#34;2018-04-23&#34;,&#34;2018-04-18&#34;,&#34;2018-04-17&#34;,&#34;2018-04-13&#34;,&#34;2018-04-13&#34;,&#34;2018-04-12&#34;,&#34;2018-04-12&#34;,&#34;2018-04-12&#34;,&#34;2018-04-02&#34;,&#34;2018-04-02&#34;,&#34;2018-03-27&#34;,&#34;2018-03-27&#34;,&#34;2018-03-25&#34;,&#34;2018-03-21&#34;,&#34;2018-03-21&#34;,&#34;2018-03-20&#34;,&#34;2018-03-20&#34;,&#34;2018-03-16&#34;,&#34;2018-03-15&#34;],[&#34;Retweeting this again as a test case for finally, actually implementing the damn thing. A functional twitter dashboard based on my retweets is minutes away (hopefully...) https://t.co/sERHmJ4TMq&#34;,&#34;This is a really useful thread for thinking about how to prevent/catch mistakes in our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Word Clouds in R from Conference Tweets</title>
      <link>/post/conference-twitter-hashtag-wordclouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conference-twitter-hashtag-wordclouds/</guid>
      <description>It’s been just about a week since the Speech-Language and Audiology Canada (SAC) Conference. Clinical researchers in speech-pathology and audiology from all across Canada came to take part in three days of talks, poster presentations, product demos, and planning meetings. Because the conference is so large, there tend to be several overlapping sessions at once. There’s pretty much something there for everyone, but there’s also a good chance that you’ll be torn between attending two sessions that overlap and have to choose one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop materials: Using R Markdown to generate reports and manuscripts (&#43; an accidental narrative)</title>
      <link>/post/workshop-using-r-markdown-to-generate-summary-reports-and-manuscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workshop-using-r-markdown-to-generate-summary-reports-and-manuscripts/</guid>
      <description>This past Tuesday we had our second R-Ladies #LdnOnt meet up of the year. The topic was using R Markdown to generate summary reports and manuscripts, led by yours truly. The original purpose of this post was to merely alert you, dear readers (all three of you) to the existence of the materials for this workshop, which are now posted online on our Github…
 ⚠️ Consider this a warning that all that lies ahead for the remainder of this post is narrative text; all useful links and tidbits related to the main title of this post can be found at the link above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>